どうして
Why?
何だ
What happened?
おい
Hey!
Shoma!
晶馬君
ねえ　晶馬君
Shoma!
晶馬君
くるくる回る
く
る
回
<< kurukuru mawaru kimi no hitomi >>
<< Round and round, your eyes wander around >>
くるくる回る
君の瞳探して回る
君
の
瞳
くるくる回る
探
し
て
回
る
くるくる回る
君の瞳探して回る
<< sagashite mawaru eki no home >>
<< Searching around the station's platforms >>
君の瞳探して回る
駅のホーム
駅
の
ホー
ム
君の瞳探して回る
駅のホーム
響くファンファーレ
響
駅のホーム
く
ファン
ファー
レ
駅のホーム
<< hibiku fanfare >>
<< The sound of fanfare from afar >>
響くファンファーレ
ガラガラ音を立てる街
ガ
ラ
音
を
立
て
る
街
<< garagara oto wo tateru machi >>
<< The clamorous city making noise >>
ガラガラ音を立てる街
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
と
り
あ
ガラガラ音を立てる街
え
ず
耳
ガラガラ音を立てる街
を
貸
し
て
み
ガラガラ音を立てる街
た
の
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
<< toriaezu mimi wo kashite ita no >>
<< I tried to keep an ear out for all this >>
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
もうすぐ消えるはずの世界に
も
う
す
ぐ
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
消
え
る
は
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
ず
の
世
界
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
に
<< mousugu kieru hazu no sekai ni >>
<< In a world that's about to end >>
もうすぐ消えるはずの世界に
ごめんね
ご
め
ん
ね
<< gomen ne >>
<< I'm sorry >>
ごめんね
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
も
う
二
度
と
会
え
な
い
よ
う
な
そ
ん
な
気
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
が
し
<< mou nido to aenai youna sonna ki ga shite >>
<< I just had a feeling I would never see you again >>
て
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
運命が笑う
運
命
が
笑
う
<< unmei ga warau >>
<< Fate is laughing at us >>
運命が笑う
臨界点突破してんだ
臨
界
点
突
破
し
て
ん
だ
<< rinkaiten toppa shiten da >>
<< I'm already past the point of no return >>
臨界点突破してんだ
限界なら既に去って
限
界
臨界点突破してんだ
な
ら
既
に
去
っ
て
<< genkai nara sude ni satte >>
<< Far over my limit >>
限界なら既に去って
絶対的支配だって
絶
対
的
支
配
限界なら既に去って
だ
っ
て
<< zettaiteki shihai datte >>
<< Even your absolute control has >>
絶対的支配だって
崩壊
崩
壊
絶対的支配だって
<< houkai >>
<< Crumbled >>
崩壊
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
終
末
理
論
は
机
上
の
空
論
で
し
か
な
<< shuumatsu riron wa kijou no kuuron shika naitte >>
<< "The end of the world is nothing but a hypothesis" >>
い
っ
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
て
ゼロとイチの世界線の果てから
ゼ
ロ
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
と
イ
チ
の
世
界
線
の
果
て
か
ら
<< 0 to 1 no sekaisen no hate kara sakebu yo >>
<< Is what I'm crying out from other side of the binary world line >>
ゼロとイチの世界線の果てから
叫ぶよ
叫
ぶ
よ
叫ぶよ
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
も
う
す
ぐ
君
が
会
い
に
く
る
よ
う
な
気
が
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
し
<< mou sugu kimi ga ai ni kuru you na ki ga shite >>
<< I have a feeling you'll come see me soon >>
て
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
僕は目を閉じるよ
僕
は
目
を
閉
じ
る
よ
<< boku wa me wo tojiru yo >>
<< So I will be waiting with my eyes closed >>
僕は目を閉じるよ
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作,仅供学习交流之用
若您喜欢本作品,请支持正版影像制品
---诸神字幕组---
日听 xHunter
翻译：英英 校对：凌可乐
时间轴：绯桜闲   压制：笑眯咪
Sheesh, he's napping so peacefully.
ったく
平和そうな顔して　寝込めやがって
They say idiots don't catch colds, but apparently they don't get hurt either.
馬鹿は風邪引かないっていうが　怪我もしないんだな
Should you be saying that?
そんな事言っていいの
You turned white as a sheet when the hospital called us.
冠ちゃん　病院から電話の来たときは真っ青になって　（兄貴　ひまり）
Bro? Himari?
Shut up!
うるさい　晶馬には絶対言うなよ
Don't you dare tell Shoma that!
Oh, it's already morning?
まさか
いけねぇ　朝ご飯の用意しなくちゃ
Shoot, I have to prepare breakfast–
いって　って
Ow!
Sho?
晶ちゃん
Shoma!
晶馬
This is a… hospital?
あれ　ここ　病院
You idiot!
馬鹿
Whatever, just go back to sleep.
もういい　そこで死んでろ
Ow!
って　何するんだよ
What'd you do that for?
Don't you remember what happened yesterday?
昨日の事覚えてないの
You got hit by a car and sent to the hospital.
晶ちゃん　車に撥ねられて　入院したんだよ
You remember now?
思い出したか
Yeah.
うん
If your memory is intact, your brain must be fine.
記憶が確かなら　おつむの方も大丈夫だな
After all, you've always been a slowpoke.
少々回転が鈍いのは元からだ
Don't worry. You didn't break any bones.
安心しろ
骨折もないし　軽い打撲だけだってさ
It's just some minor bumps and bruises.
The doctor was amazed at how mild your injuries were!
医者も運がいいって笑ってたよ
He may be acting tough now,
あのね　こんな事言ってるけど
but Kan stayed up all night by your bedside.
冠ちゃん　昨日から一睡もしないで　晶ちゃんに付き切りで
Himari!
ひまり
Oh, that reminds me.
あ　そうだ
I'll go get Ringo.
私リンゴちゃん呼んでくるね
Make sure you thank her too, Sho.
晶ちゃんもちゃんと礼言うんだよ
Ringo called the ambulance and stayed with you the whole time.
リンゴちゃん　救急車呼んで　ずっと付き添ってくれてたんだから
Ringo?
リンゴちゃん　晶ちゃん　今起きたよ
Sho just woke up.
He's alive and kicking.
すっごく元気　リンゴちゃんにお礼が言いたいって
He wants to thank you.
どうしたの　入っておいてよ
What's wrong?
Come on in.
No.
駄目　そんな資格ない
I have no right to.
Ringo?
リンゴちゃん
So?
ね　結局のところ何があった
What happened exactly?
Your accident had something to do with her item, right?
お前の事故　荻野目リンゴの例の物と何か関係があるんだろう
Don't tell me– she pushed you?
まさか　あの女に突き飛ばされて
ち　違うよ　なんて言うか　その
N-No!
Well, I... screwed up again.
僕がまたどじだって言うか　余計な事言ったって言うか
I said something I shouldn't have…
In any case, it was just an accident.
とにかくこれは純然たる事故だよ
Not her fault.
あの子のせいじゃないよ
Shoma...
晶馬君
Hey, Kan.
ねえ　冠ちゃん
Have you ever gotten a present from a girl?
女の子からプレゼントってもらった事ある
Why do you wanna know all of a sudden?
いきなり何の話だよ
You're popular with girls, right?
だって　冠ちゃんモテるんでしょう
Sho says you're a player.
すけこましだって晶ちゃんが
That idiot's giving her weird ideas again?
あのバカまたひまりに妙な事を
So, I wanted to ask,
それでね　聞きたい事があるんだけど
what kind of gifts do you like to get from girls?
冠ちゃんが女の子からもらって嬉しかったものってある
Well...
そうだな　いや他の女から　欲しいものなんて
There isn't really anything...
I want from other girls.
まぁ　特にないから
Oh, how about...
そっか　じゃ　じゃ　さ
things you hated getting instead?
逆にこれは嫌ってものは
Ah, there are lot's of 'em!
ああ　それなら　けっこうあるぞ
All that "I made it with love" kind of stuff.
例えば　私が真心込めて作りましたっ系のもの
ああいうのはパスだな
No thank you.
ほら　弁当とかでもさ
You know those overly complicated bento?
妙に手が込んでるやつ
Like wieners cut into absurd shapes,
ありえない複雑な切れ目の入ったタコさんウインナとか
or a sushi roll with animals or flowers on it!
断面が花だの動物だの絵に成ってる巻き寿司とか
Those things send a chill down my spine.
ああいうのは正直ぞっとするよ
So, bento is out of the question?
なら　お弁当はエヌジーって事
Also, there was this humongous cake.
後は　　馬鹿デカイケーキとかが
The one with a wedding cake topper!
ウエディングドレス着たカップル人形が頂上に乗ってたりしてさ
Man, that was a shocker!
確かにあれは相当きってたな
I-Is that all?
そ　それだけ　他には
Anything else?
Well, the worst is probably a hand-made sweater.
そうだな　でも　やっぱり一番きついのは手編みのセーターか
Oversized and has your name on it.
でかでかと名前いりでさ　あれは重い
Way too creepy!
When they force me to wear it, it makes me want to...
しかもそれを着ろと強要された日には
So... You'd hate getting a scarf too?
じゃ　マフラーとかも　やっぱ迷惑かな
まさか
No way!
Listen, Himari.
いいか　ひまり　今のは全部冗談だ
I was kidding about everything I just said!
No man in this world is dumb enough to complain about a knitted gift from you!
ひまりが編んでくれたものにケチをつけるような馬鹿はこの世に存在しない
If you made a scarf for me,
俺はひまりがくれたマフラーなら　何時でも　何処でも
I'd wear it anywhere, anytime!
例え灼熱のサハラ砂漠の真ん中だろうか
Even if I was in middle of the Sahara Desert,
茹だれような熱帯のジャングルだろうか　巻きこなして見せる
or in a steaming hot jungle!
I'd always have it on!
I'd be like banzai! Viva la scarf!
手編み万歳
ブィブァ　マフラー
Kan, I've gotten to a good stopping point,
冠ちゃん　私切りのいいところまで編んだから
so I'll go home and get Sho's change of clothes.
一度家に戻って　晶ちゃんの着替え取ってくるね
So, please stay with him.
だから冠ちゃんは　晶ちゃんと一緒に居てあげて
Roger.
ラジャー
You kept it a secret for me.
あの時の事　黙っていてくれたんだ
I thought when you saw Kanba and Himari, you'd tell them the truth...
私　冠葉君とひまりちゃんの顔見たら　本当の事
I'm sorry!
御免なさい
You scraped your knees.
膝擦り剥いちゃったね
Huh?
Were you hurt anywhere else?
他に怪我は
No...
ううん
I see. That's great.
そう　よかった
Don't worry.
別にそんなに深刻にならないでよ
It's just some bumps and bruises.
怪我も大した事なかったし　入院なんて　大げさなんだ
I can't believe they admitted me for that.
Besides, I said some awful things to you back then...
それにあの時は僕も酷い事言っちゃったから
I'm sorry!
御免なさい
Don't worry about it.
だから　もういいって
More importantly, is the diary all right?
それより日記は大丈夫だった
Um... I'm heading home now.
あのう　今日は帰る
I'll be back.
また来るから
Your diary?!
日記が
It's ripped!
それ　破れてるじゃないか
Half of it was stolen.
とられたの　半分
What do you mean?
どういう事
You know how I dropped it on the sidewalk yesterday?
昨日道路にこれを落としたでしょう
When I got it back, someone on a bike...
あの時バイクに乗った誰かに
そんな
No way...
Gosh, it must be crushed soon.
嫌だわ　早くすり潰さないと
Time for your dinner, Mr. Takakura.
高倉さん　御食事ですよ
You must be hungry.
お腹空いたでしょう
There's a delicious dessert for you today.
今日は特別に美味しいデザートもあるんですよ
Here you go.
はい　どうぞ
One disaster after another.
一難去ってまた一難
Gosh, we ran out of tea.
あら　嫌だ　お茶が切れてしまったわ
I'll go get some, then.
じゃあ　あたしがもらってきます
Thank you.
ありがとう
The kitchen is a bit far. Do you know where it is?
給湯室ちょっと離れてるけど　分かるかしら
はい
Yes.
How enviable of you, Mr. Takakura.
羨ましいですね　高倉さん
You've had your girlfriend taking care of you this whole time.
彼女が付き切りで看病してくれるなんて
No, she's not my…
いや　あの子はそういうん
Really, how enviable of you.
本当に　羨ましい事
お待たせ　お茶
Sorry to keep you waiting! I got...
晶馬君
Shoma?
Thanks for waiting, Esmeralda.
お待たせ　エスメラルダ
Now we have the bait for our prey.
これで獲物を誘き寄せる　囮は手に入れた
サア　ハンティングを始めましょう
Let the hunt begin.
What do you mean he's gone?
いなくなったってどういう事だよ
I don't know.
分かんない
I thought he was eating lunch,
お昼を食べてたはずなんだけど　私が戻って来た時には
but when I came back...
It's from Shoma!
晶馬からだ
What?!
Shoma
Hand over "half of the diary."
Otherwise,
Shoma Takakura is dead.
"Half of the diary."
日記の半分
What does that mean?
どういう事だ
P.S.
Right now, Shoma Takakura is...
This is...
これは
Who on Earth would blackmail us for the diary?
日記が交換条件って
一体誰が
Um... here.
あのう　これ
Only the first half?
前半だけ
Where's the rest?
残りは
It was stolen last night.
昨日の夜取られたの
Stolen? By whom?
取られたって　誰にだよ
分からない
I don't know.
A bike came out of nowhere, then...
いきなりバイクが来て　無理やり　それで
I spaced out.
ふらついちゃって　車に撥ねられそうになった私を晶馬君が
Shoma came and saved me when a car was about to...
It doesn't sound like a lie.
嘘じゃなさそうだな
Of course not!
当たり前じゃない
If Shoma hadn't saved me, I'd be...
晶馬君が助けてくれなかったら　今頃私
ああ　ここに干したパンツがなくなってるわ
The panties I hung up are gone.
Take it!
持て行って
Shoma's life is in danger if you don't hand it over, right?
それがないと　晶馬君が危ないんでしょう
Then hurry!
だったら　速く
Are you sure?
いいのか
Otherwise...
だって　そうしないとは
Shoma
Kanba Takakura, bring the "diary",
and come to C-Ward's rooftop.
まあ　待て
Hold on.
Shoma is safe, for now.
とりあえず　晶馬はまだ無事だ　それにこちにも手がないわけじゃない
And it's not like we're out of options.
あやあや　私のパンティーがないわ
What?
My panties are missing.
お婆ちゃん　今探してるから
I'm looking for them, Grandma!
Kanba Takakura, bring the "diary",
and come to C-Ward's rooftop.
Shoma
Kanba Takakura, bring the "diary",
and come to C-Ward's rooftop.
メールは晶馬の携帯から発信されてるって事は
If the emails are being sent from Shoma's phone...
Kanba Takakura, bring the "diary",
and come to C-Ward's rooftop.
Shoma
To'oh General Hospital
As I thought.
やっぱりな
Did you find him?
見つかったの
Yeah, Shoma is locked up somewhere in this hospital.
ああ　晶馬はこの病院の何処かに監禁されている
You hold on to this.
これはお前が持ってろ
Even if it's just half of it, this is something Himari...
仮令半分になって言ようと
これはひまりに俺たちに必要なものだ
Something we need.
We're not going to hand it over, no matter what.
何があろうと　絶対に渡さない
But if we don't, Shoma will...
だけど　持って行かなかったら　晶馬君が
I'll definitely save Shoma.
晶馬は俺が必ず助ける　約束する
I promise.
So you protect this.
だから　これはお前が守れ
Isn't it something so precious that you couldn't let it go, even with him following you all this time?
あいつを散々連れまわして
それでも渡せない程大事な物なんだろう
Yes, but...
そうだけど
I brought the diary, as promised!
約束通り　日記は持って来た
Come and get it!
速く取りに来い
They saw right through my plan.
バレバレか
There you are!
そっちか
Huh?
This is...
これは
Do you remember now?
どうだ　思い出したか
何の事だ　何を思い出せって
What are you talking about?
Remember what?
You still can't remember?
これでも思い出せないか
Still?
Can't you remember?
これでもか　これでもか
Wear it.
それを着ろ　お前に選択の余地はない
It's your only option.
どうだ
How about it?
You've finally remembered?
終に思い出したな
ああ　思い出したよ
Yeah, I remembered.
Shoma.
晶馬君
Shoma?
Who is this?
だれ
Kanba Takakura was sent on a wild goose chase.
高倉冠葉への指令はトラップだ
Bring the diary, Ringo Oginome.
日記は　荻野目リッゴ　お前が持って来い
Otherwise, Shoma Takakura dies.
さもなくば　高倉晶馬は死ぬ
Drop the diary from there.
そこから　日記を落とせ
I'm sorry, Momoka.
御免ね　桃果
Wait!
待て　どうして
Why?
Shoma?
晶馬
Hey, stop messing around!
おい　フザケたマネは止せ
早く晶馬を解放しろ
Hurry up and let Shoma go!
やっと思い出した
Did you finally remember?
You!
お前
That sweater looks good on you.
そのセーターお似合いね
やっぱりあなたにはピジョンブラッド
Pigeon Blood.
The crimson red of pigeon's blood sure suits you the best.
ハートの血の赤が一番似合う
言えよ　お前の狙いは何だ
Tell me what you're after!
How do you know about the diary?!
どうして　日記の事を知っている
Right.
そうね
The treacherous hero who followed
Ariadne's red thread all the way here
アリヤドネの赤い糸を手繰って
ここまでやって来た不実な勇者様には
deserves a little reward.
何かご褒美をあげなくては
Very well.
いい　一つだけ教えてあげる
I'll tell you one thing.
What I'm after is...
私の狙いは
She disappeared?
消えた
なにこれ
Bro! Did she...
兄貴　あいつは
Yeah.
I have obtained the diary, as planned.
予定通り　日記は手に入れた
I can't wait for what'll happen next.
これからは楽しみね　エスメラルダ
Slogan
Today's
Right, Esmeralda?
Cherish Your
Memories
まだ狩りは始まったばかりだもの
The hunt has only just begun.
Of course, Project M will be completed.
勿論プロジェクトMは完成する
I am not a pathetic hunter
私は獲物を取り逃がすような愚かなハンターでは　なくてよ
who lets her prey escape.
Survival Strategy!
生存戦略ー
Yes, you're right.
ええ　そう　そうの通りよ
Mario.
マリオさん
Because I Love Him
subete ga moshi kimerarete tara
If everything was written in stone
全てが欲しい
繋がれたいたら
bokura wa doushite mogaku no darou
Why have we been resisting our fate?
僕らはどうして
もがくのだろう
sore wa kimi ja nai
It's not you
それは君じゃない
kimi no sei ja nai
It's not your fault
君のせいじゃない
苦しみはもう沢山なんだ
kanashimi wa mou takusan nanda
I've had enough misery
dakara sou ja nai
You're mistaken
だからそうじゃない
夢のままじゃない
ima no mama ja nai
Fate can be changed
umaku tsutaekirenai kedo
I can't explain it, but
上手く伝えきれないけど
Dear my future
Dear your future
Dear you future
I have lost it.
私はそれを失った
But the destiny will not change.
でも運命は変わらない
We will become one.
私達は一つになるから
So, you no longer have anything to do with me!
あなたと私はもう関係ないのよ
Survival Strategy. It's too revealing.
生存戦略　見えすぎちゃって困るの